My name is Cynthia.
I am one of the thousands of Nigerians that were deported from Libya.
These are my colleagues; we came back from Libya together.
I went to Libya 8 years ago; I was 18 years old at that time.
I didn't know anything, I was still very young.
At that point in time, I was learning hair dressing.
I was dating a particular guy at that point in time who then told me about the journey to Libya.
He gave me some connection; that if I go, I will be able to make it over there.
I closed my salon and everything and followed him.
When we got there, he sold me to a Nigerian woman who was into human trafficking.
We could sleep with 20 - 30 men a day, just to be able to pay the money.
I was so depressed and didn't know what to do.
They told me that if I didn't pay the money,
they would kill me and throw my body into the desert
where my family members would never hear from me again.
So I had no option but to just do the job.
While in the house there, we heard gunshots.
Everybody had it in their mind to run; who could run, would run.
I was not able to run and they caught me.
While in prison, the wardens that were taking care of us
were talking to some Nigerians there.
While they were talking to a Nigerian and threatening him with a gun,
that was how I was being shot on my leg.
On my left leg.
There was no treatment over there.
I just stayed there, staying in one position for almost 4 months.
I was not able to walk or do anything by myself.
I was just in one position.
With the assistance of my friends and colleagues, I was able to go to the bathroom.
It affected my hands, I couldn't move my hands.
I decided to return to Nigeria.
One day, I was very sick over there, whilst working for the woman.
The sickness affected me and I had to cut my hair.
I was very weak and I was losing strength.
I begged the woman that I couldn't work for that day, that she should pardon me.
She refused.
She used the stick that is used to turn 'eba' to beat me severely
and put ground pepper in my private part.
I started rolling on the floor, screaming and
shouting for help
but I didn't see anybody that would help me.
She sat down there, seeing me rolling, screaming and shouting.
She didn't answer me at all.
After that, I left because of the condition of my leg; I was left with a wound.
Because I didn't have better treatment, the
gunshot bullet was affecting my whole body.
I became weak and very sick.
I was looking so pale and I lost strength.
So I went to stay with one of my friends.
While I was there, I was caught the second time.
They gave us an option that we should return to our country.
That even if we didn't make it over there, by returning to our country, we would be able to make it here.
So, I decided to return to my country to start all over.
That was how I was deported to Nigeria.
Can you show us where you had the gunshot wound?
I was shot here; the bullet passed here and came out from underneath my leg.
I was very sick when I came back because from my waist downward, I was affected.
I was very weak and losing strength.
When I came here, they assigned me to some doctors,
they gave me some medication that helped me to be able to sleep and eat well.
I was able to walk well, though I am still feeling pains but I am bearing the pain.
My advice to young people is that they should not try this thing,
this illegal journey because it is not good.
People might post different pictures on the internet that may make you think the place is good,
"Ah, they are making money there and they are doing well!"
The place is not good.
They don't treat us Nigerians well; they beat and treat people like us there like slaves.
My advice to parents, please take care of your children.
Don't give your children out to people who are doing human trafficking.
They may not tell you what they are
taking your children to go and do over there.
They would just tell you that they want to take your child to go over there to do something.
At the end of the day, they would change the whole story for you.
So please, parents, be careful of such people.
Young girls of nowadays, it is not good to date at an early stage
because in my case, it was through the person I was dating that I got into all these things.
My name is Mary. I was among the thousands that were deported from Libya.
I went to Libya because things were not moving well for me.
I have no parents; nobody to take care of us and my younger siblings.
I was trying to give them a better future.
When I was learning hair dressing, I was explaining to my friend,
"Look at the situation we are in. There is nobody to help".
My friend advised me to travel.
That if I travelled, I would be able to take good care of my younger siblings.
That if I looked at my friends who have travelled, they have acquired cars and houses.
That if I went there, I would be able to take care of my family.
I decided to travel; there was nobody to advice me.
When I started on the journey, it was so tough and I could not come back.
The journey was 50/50 and I had to continue with the journey.
If I die, I die. Or I get saved. So I continued the journey.
I went to the desert - we trekked for 8 hours in the desert with no water or food.
We spent some days in the desert and then they brought us back.
They said that we must continue the journey because there was no more going back.
So many people were dying; children were dying.
They would dig the ground and bury people alive.
God helped me and I was able to pass that desert in the hot sun.
The sun is like fire on the head.
I got to Libya.
When I got there, the friend that deceived me in going there abandoned me.
He did not pay the money I used to go to Libya.
So they then sold me.
When they sold me, the man said that I had to do prostitution.
I told him I vowed in my life never to do prostitution.
It is not good and a sin against God.
He insisted I must do it and he beat me up.
He stripped me naked, and took my picture.
He cut my hair and finger nails, and
took my bra and underwear.
He threatened to post it on the internet to show what I was doing.
I told him it is not good and I can't do it.
He said I must pay the money.
He beat me every day.
I had no choice; I cried every day doing prostitution.
In a day, about 10 men would sleep with me.
I would be crying.
Those that would be sleeping with me, when they saw me crying,
I would tell them that that job was not for me.
They would go to the man and tell him that they wanted to help me.
The man would refuse and insist that I must do that prostitution.
So I had no choice.
He would beat me and put a bottle inside my private part.
That I must do it.
Anytime I worked, he collected the money.
The police then came to the place, to come and bust that place.
They took me to prison.
I was in prison, with no food or water.
I just asked God to help me,
because I was always praying, telling God to see me through.
This work was not for me. Even if I was poor, but God should help me.
I was praying, "When will I came back to Nigeria? Nigeria is good".
Many Africans were dying.
The journey is not good; the road is very bad.
We were finally deported to Nigeria.
I came back to Nigeria with nothing.
All the work I did was in vain.
When we came here yesterday, the man of God took good care of us.
He took us to the hospital.
He listened to our stories.
So I decided that today, I must come to the church to testify.
I am very happy.
How old are you?
I am 27 years old.
How long did you spend over there?
I spent 2 years.
Okay, two years.
I would advice the young girls not to travel illegally;
they should not listen to anyone because they would come with sweet words,
telling you nice things about the journey.
It is not good to enter into a relationship at a young age.
I entered into a relationship at a young age because I had no helper.
I don't want my sisters to enter into a relationship at a young age.
I want them to live a better life.
I am here, thanking God for what He has done for me.
I thought I was never going to come back to Nigeria
because I wasn't allowed to make a call whilst I was in Libya.
My family never knew where I was.
But I thank God for bringing me here.
Okay, so you mean you actually regret going on this journey?
Yes.
And do you now value your country better than where you were traveling to?
Okay. We have listened to the sister.
Can we listen to the next person?
I am Washington, I am a Liberian.
It was my friend who encouraged me to embark on this journey.
He told me that I am a mechanic and I can travel to work as a mechanic over there
because there is much money in it.
So I embarked on the journey. When I got to Libya, they kidnapped me.
I called one of my friends in Liberia.
He sent me 1,700 US dollars to free me from the kidnappers.
Our brother says his name is Washington and he is originally from Liberia.
He is one of the deportees from Libya.
He was actually deceived by a friend to come over to Germany
through an illegal route, passing through Libya.
When he was traveling, he was arrested and faced a lot of torture in Libya.
In the prison, I was beaten every morning and evening.
When my friend paid the money, the kidnappers refused to free me.
I had one Nigerian friend in prison.
He said that when he got to Libya, he was kidnapped and put in prison.
In prison, he was calling his family to bail him out.
But he could not get in touch with his family to bail him out.
It was one of his friends that paid the money to bail him out.
Even after paying the money, they refused to release him from prison.
The Nigerian man I met there told me he got the key to the prison
and he could open the prison door so that everyone inside can escape.
He opened it and everyone climbed on the fence and jumped down unto the desert.
We were in the desert for three days.
He said while they were in prison and many other people with him,
there was a Nigerian man who happened to get the keys to the prison.
the man opened the prison door and they all ran out.
He spent three days in the desert without food and water.
In the desert, we scattered; we were six per group.
As we were going, they kidnapped four persons; I and my brother escaped.
He said while they were escaping through the desert,
they divided themselves into groups of six people.
In his own group of six, four were captured and taken to the prison
while himself and one other person managed to escape.
When we escaped, we went to our big man's place.
We stayed indoors, we couldn't come outside.
We were in the house throughout.
That day, he told us he would send us to Italy.
That same day, they caught us again.
The police put me in prison; I was there for 8 months.
He said after that time, he managed to find his way to the sea,
trying to cross over the Mediterranean sea to Europe.
The day he was waiting to go on that journey on the sea,
himself and other people were captured and put in the prison.
They were arrested and he spent 8 months in prison.
I was seeing other people going to their country
but there was no flight from Libya to my country.
So, I decided to declare myself as Nigerian in order to come to Nigeria.
While in the prison, I heard about Prophet T.B. Joshua.
So, I decided to come to The SCOAN for him to send me back to Liberia.
He said while he was in the prison, he started hearing about
the man of God, Prophet T.B. Joshua, and about the church
and how the man of God has been helping the deportees from Libya.
When they come back to the country, the man of God would help them,
trying to integrate them back into the society and establish them.
He said that the organisations that were deporting them to different countries came
and people from different countries were deported.
But for him, there were no flight going to his country
because he was the only Liberian in the prison.
So what he had to do was to lie that he was a Nigerian
so that he could come with the Nigerian people.
That is why he is in Nigeria today.
Mr Washington
Libya Deportee Shares Experience
So he said because of what he has been hearing
how the man of God has been helping people,
he believed that if he came to Nigeria,
God would use the man of God, Prophet T.B. Joshua, to help him get back to Liberia.
While in the prison, my Nigerian friend told me that if I was not careful, I would fail the interview.
He decided to teach me.
When they asked me where I came from, I should tell them that I was from Kaduna State.
When they asked me about the local government, I should tell them it was Sanga.
He wrote it on a piece of paper and I practised it.
When I sat for the first test, I failed in the first test; I was the third person.
They now gave me number 50; I went all the way back.
I started crying because if I failed the tests,
if I didn't go back to my country, I would surely die in that prison.
because I was the only Liberian in that prison; there was no flight to Liberia.
Even in Libya, I couldn't call Liberia because the call wouldn't go through.
If I wanted to call my mum, I would call through Guinea
and tell the person to call my mum. My mum would then call me.
That's how I used to communicate with my mum.
He said while in the prison, it was even difficult to call his family in Liberia.
While others were interviewed, documentations were done
and they were deported to their country, he faced a lot of challenges.
He was not a Nigerian and so when he went for the interview,
he was not able to say the right thing.
But there was a Nigerian brother that was teaching him what to say -
from this State and local government - but each time he would fail.
So they were taking him back into the prison again
where he would start crying and begging them so they gave him another chance.
Then he was able to scale through the interview and got the documents to come to Nigeria.
How long did you spend over there in Libya?
I spent eight months in prison.
The whole time I was in Libya, I was in prison throughout; I never came out.
And you couldn't get to your destination, Europe?
Yes, I couldn't get to my destination.
So what advice do you have for people who are listening to you now?
Youngsters all over the place, in every country, what advice do you have for them?
The advice I have for my friends all over the world is
that you should never use this route to go anywhere.
Don't let anyone fool you on Facebook that so and so thing is going on,
I want you to come to so and so place.
If you don't have the money to fly to a country, don't use the desert road to go anywhere;
don't use the sea route to go anywhere.
Okay, so our brother is advising everyone, especially the youth,
that if you want to travel, travel through the right channel, through legal means.
Don't go by an illegal route, don't allow anyone to lure or deceive you
that everything would be fine.
He is coming from there and nothing is actually fine.
It is a regrettable journey; he doesn't want anyone to experience what he has experienced.
So what do you want now? You are now in Nigeria, what exactly do you want?
I even came without clothing and the man of God gave me clothes, food and shelter.
Okay. You heard from the brother. He said he came with nothing
and the man of God gave him money to get clothes, send him for medical treatment,
before he now came to share this experience today.
So, what do you want now?
I want to tell the man of God to please help me and send me back to my country.
That is all that I want from him, I want to go back to my country.
I miss my people so much.
So you are begging to go back to your country now?
I want to go back, I really want to go back.
Okay, that is a lesson for everyone that no matter how bad your country is,
the situation of your county is, home is home and there is no place like home.
He has gone on the journey, just like others.
They have experienced the other side of other countries.
Now, they begged to come back to their country and are appreciating their country better.
For God Almighty to bring you back safely, we believe He has a plan for your life.
All the experiences you have passed
through is to help you for your future. Amen!
Amen!
Thank you very much.
My name is Danazumi.
I am one of the thousand immigrants that were deported from Libya.
On going to Libya, there were about 50 cars carrying us through the desert.
On the way, many people died and some fainted.
There was no food and water in the desert - for many days, about one month.
Some people spent one month, some several weeks and some about seven days in the desert.
In Libya, we were arrested by some men who used us to look for money.
They asked us to call our parents to pay some ransom.
We called our parents with their phone.
I called my parents and told them that I was kidnapped by some men
and they asked me to pay the sum of 700,000 Naira.
My mum shouted, "Where do you expect me to get that amount of money from?
Did you tell me that you were travelling?"
I said, "That is not the question now.
The question is: How am I going to leave from here?"
She then told me, "I have nothing to do. I will not kill myself because of you".
She was angry, so, I began to plead with her, "I beg, please help me in this situation".
She thought that I was lying.
The day when she saw me that I was being hanged,
which is called 'monkey hanging' -
they called her through video call, they were videoing me, beating me -
she began to cry on the phone, saying, "What is she going to do?"
I told her to run around and maybe sell the plot of land,
or to do any other thing to raise the money to help me out.
She did whatever she could and helped me out of there.
When I got out, I looked for where to hustle to get money to feed
because I didn't want to call my mother again for money.
I started working with a man who carried me to work every day and also gave me food.
He said he would pay me after seven days.
When the seventh day reached, I went to meet him,
"I beg, I want to collect the money you said you will pay me".
He said, "Which money?"
I thought to myself that if we were in Nigeria, this man would give me the money by force.
I tried to force him to give me the money.
The man asked me to wait for him.
I thought he was going to bring the money.
He went inside and came out with an AK-47 in his hand.
I thought to myself that if I ran, he would shoot me,
so it would be better to wait for him to beat me up.
The man used the gun and flogged me continuously.
I was thanking God that the man did not shoot me.
He beat me to the extent of breaking a bone on my hand.
He then allowed me and I left that place.
I went to my friend's place to ask them to help me.
We have listened to the brother; many of us could not actually understand him.
He was speaking in pidgin English to express himself very well.
He said he was one of the people that travelled to Libya through an illegal route.
Before he left, he never told his mother or any member of his family
until when he got there, he was kidnapped, put in the cell
and was asked to pay a ransom of 700,000 Naira.
He contacted his mother and told her that kidnappers were demanding 700,000 Naira.
The mother could not afford it and she had sell a plot of land and other things to raise the money.
After he was released from the prison, he went out and got someone who offered him a job.
He would be paying him after every seven days.
After working for seven days, he went to the man and demanded his money.
The man asked him, "What money? Which money are you talking about?"
He told the man, "But our agreement was that you would pay me after seven days".
The man told him, "Ok, wait for me".
He said that he was trying to be stubborn to the man; he thought he was in his country.
But before he knew, it was too late.
When the man went in, he thought the man was going to bring the money to pay him.
Rather, the man brought out an AK-47 rifle.
He couldn't run because he believed that the man was going to shoot him.
So he waited and the man used the AK-47 to hit him.
That was how he sustained this broken arm.
I went home to meet my friends and told them
that I want to go to the hospital to get treatment.
My friend asked me, "Do you know where you are?
Do you have anything to go to the hospital with?
You cannot go to the hospital in this country.
We will help you to tie the hand; you will carry it like that".
That is how they tied the hand and I was in that condition for almost seven months.
I was going up and down with this hand, looking for a way to go back to my country
or go further to get treatment for the hand.
There was no solution until I was arrested.
Okay, can you tell us what advice you have for people who are listening to you now?
Remember, you left your country hale and hearty
and now you are back with a broken arm and a terrible experience over there.
What advice do you have for people, especially the youth?
My advice to everyone watching me now is that
you can see that I have come back with a broken arm
with nothing - all the money was being wasted.
They should be careful with the kind of friends they mingle with.
Parents should take good care of their children
and find out what they are doing - whether it is right or wrong.
They should be careful of the lies people tell them about this journey,
"In two or three days, you are going to be there".
They are telling you lies, just to collect money.
No one should embark on this journey because it is very deadly.
Many people die on the sea and on the land.
I want to advise them to always stay in their country to hustle.
I believe that one day God will make a way
and God will bless them and they will become something in life.
Our brothers and sisters who have come today to share their experiences,
as we can see, they are in helpless need of assistance to be able to start life again.
In view of this, the anointed man of God says help is the best investment.
We should make a tangible contribution to the life of others.
With the support of the Emmanuel TV partners,
the man of God, Prophet T.B. Joshua has asked us to give
the sum of 200,000 Naira to each of our brothers and sisters here.
Libya Deportees Each Receive 200,000 Naira
From T.B. Joshua And Emmanuel TV Partners
That is the sum of 200,000 Naira cash each,
and 'The Mirror' book offered by the anointed man of God for the salvation of your soul.
Remember that whatever the man of God does is for the salvation of souls
so that they can go back and make something meaningful with their lives.
They can get into a business, trade, and be able to get back on their feet again
and never think of going through this kind of journey again.
Libya Deportees Each Receive 200,000 Naira
From T.B. Joshua And Emmanuel TV Partners
Before we hear from them, we also want to inform our Liberian brother
that since he is looking for assistance to go back to his country,
we are here to announce to you that the ministry will assist you to get all the documents,
flight and everything to get back to your country, Liberia.
Thank you so much, Man of God.
God will bless you for helping us and for changing our lives.
God will continue to protect you.
Your pockets shall never be dry, in Jesus' name!
Thank you, Man of God, for changing my life.
I am very happy. I am the happiest person today.
Thank you, Man of God! God will give you more wisdom and anointing, in Jesus' name!
Thank you, Man of God, for wiping away our tears.
Thank you for helping us.
May the Lord continue to increase your wisdom.
May God continue to bless you, in Jesus' name!
Glory be to God.
We also want to encourage you now that you have received this assistance
to make things easy for you to be able to start life anew,
all you need to do is to make the Word of God the standard for your life.
Anywhere you go, please take time out to advise people not to go on this illegal journey.
If anyone wants to travel outside the country for a good purpose,
they should wait for God's time and go through the right channel.
We pray that God Almighty will give you the grace
to make the best use of the resources you have received,
and God Almighty who has provided this will continue the supply, in Jesus' name!
Amen!
After listening to their complaints in regards to their health, the Libya Deportees received prayer
in the power of the Holy Spirit for healing and deliverance, in the name of Jesus Christ!
Let's watch.
Man of God, please, help me.
I was shot and I have difficulty in walking.
Prophet T.B. Joshua Ministering
Prayer And Healing In Jesus' Name
Okay, come on. Stand up.
Walk!
Prophet T.B. Joshua Ministering
Prayer And Healing In Jesus' Name
Healed In Jesus' Name
Miss Mary
Libya Deportee
Prophet T.B. Joshua Ministering
Prayer And Healing In Jesus' Name
Set Free In Jesus' Name
Man of God, help me! I have a broken hand.
Prophet T.B. Joshua Ministering
Prayer And Healing In Jesus' Name
Healed In Jesus' Name
Thank You, Jesus.
Thank You, Jesus. I am free!
Mr Danazumi
Healing Testimony
My name is Akeem. I am one of the thousands that were deported.
I came back with a broken hand.
But since the man of God prayed for me, I received my healing.
Now I can move my hand and use it to eat.
Thank You, Jesus. I am free.
After listening to Mr Washington's situation, Prophet T.B. Joshua and the Emmanuel TV Partners
helped him with all the necessary documents to travel back to his country, Liberia,
including the flight ticket and also the sum of $1,000 USD so that he can start his life afresh in Liberia.
Let's watch.
STANDARD FOR LIFE
My name is Washington, I'm a Liberian.
I am one of the deportees from Libya.
There was no flight from Libya to my country,
so I decided to lie to the people that I am from Nigeria.
That's why they brought me to Nigeria.
I'm appealing to the man of God to send me back to my country.
I came without any documents.
I don't have a passport, identity card or identity document.
I'm appealing to the man of God to help me, to send me back to my country.
I can't stay in Nigeria because I am not from Nigeria.
We have heard from the young man.
He's a Liberian and he finds himself in Nigeria because he had to be deported
with other Nigerian Libyan deportees because he couldn't go back to his country, Liberia.
Now, he is stranded in Nigeria because he has no money to transport himself back to Liberia
and he doesn't have any travelling document - no passport, nothing.
He didn't even have clothes when he came.
It was the man of God that provided clothing, feeding and accommodation for him
ever since last week when they were deported from Libya.
We can see you holding a document.
What document is this?
This is the document they used to deport me from Libya to Nigeria.
This is the document that Mr Washington received after claiming that he was a Nigerian,
so that they would deport him out of Libya.
The anointed man of God, Prophet T.B. Joshua is aware of your case
and he has also responded promptly.
He has made all the necessary travelling documents available for you
to be able to travel back to your country, Liberia.
These include the police report, affidavit, travelling documents
and your flight ticket to go back to Liberia.
These are all the documents and all the expenses have been paid by Prophet T.B. Joshua.
Here is your main travelling document which replaces your passport.
With this you can travel back to your country, Liberia.
This is your flight ticket back to Liberia.
This is the affidavit.
Lastly, we have the Nigerian police report.
To God be the glory.
Mr Washington has received all the necessary documents as well as the flight ticket
that would enable him to travel legally and freely back to Liberia.
In addition to the travel documents that have been procured by Prophet T.B. Joshua - all expenses paid -
the man of God, Prophet T.B. Joshua, with the support of the Emmanuel TV Partners
has also decided to bless you with a cash gift so that when you get back to your country, Liberia
you would not have to start going around on the street or engaging yourself in any activities
that would not make you useful to the society.
The man of God has therefore asked us to give you this sum of $1000 USD.
Thank you so much.
Thank you so much, Man of God. May God bless you.
I am so happy for that. Thank you so much.
God bless you. God bless the ministry.
God bless everyone, God bless all the members of the church.
Thank you so much, Man of God.
Mr Washington Receives All The Necessary Documents, Flight Ticket To Liberia And $1000 USD To Start A New Life
TT: Lizz Ndung'u 06:08:2018
RV: Mel Flowers 03/10/2018